[
    {
        "question": "Vienna is the capital of which European country?",
        "answer": "Austria"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Somalia?",
        "answer": "Mogadishu"
    },
    {
        "question": "Suva is the capital of which Melanesian country?",
        "answer": "Fiji"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ocean is Fiji located in?",
        "answer": "Pacific"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ocean is the region of Melanesia located in?",
        "answer": "Pacific"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which four independent countries does the region of Melanesia include?",
        "answer": "Vanuatu, Solomon Islands, Fiji, and Papa New Guinea"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sucre is the capital of what country?",
        "answer": "Bolivia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Bolivia?",
        "answer": "Sucre"
    },
    {
        "question": "What New York City avenue divides the east side from the west side?",
        "answer": "Fifth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is capital of India?",
        "answer": "New Delhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Belgium?",
        "answer": "Brussels"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which US state are the Catskill Mountains located?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city in Texas is named for President James K. Polk`s Vice-President?",
        "answer": "Dallas"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which US state is the geographic center of the 48 contiguous states?",
        "answer": "Kansas"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country borders Egypt to the west?",
        "answer": "Libya"
    },
    {
        "question": "In miles, approximately, how much Atlantic coastline does the state of New Hampshire have?",
        "answer": "18"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Bohemian city gave us the Pilsner?",
        "answer": "Pilsen"
    },
    {
        "question": "A statue of Lady Godiva stands in the centre which English city?",
        "answer": "Coventry"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Oklahoma?",
        "answer": "Oklahoma City"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what nation does Panama attach onto South America?",
        "answer": "Colombia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Moosehead Lake is the largest lake in which US state?",
        "answer": "Maine"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which four US states begin with the word `New`?",
        "answer": "New Hampshire, New Jersey, New Mexico and New York"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Wyandotte Cave is located in which US state?",
        "answer": "Indiana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Louisiana?",
        "answer": "Baton Rouge"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to the southernmost reaches of the Appalachian Mountains?",
        "answer": "Alabama"
    },
    {
        "question": "The island of Martha`s Vineyard is located in what body of water?",
        "answer": "Atlantic Ocean"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country controls the Mediterranean island of Corsica?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the two-letter postal code for the state of Hawaii?",
        "answer": "HI"
    },
    {
        "question": "Suriname is part of which continent?",
        "answer": "South America"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Republic of Suriname is part of which continent?",
        "answer": "South America"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ocean does Suriname have direct water access to?",
        "answer": "Atlantic Ocean"
    },
    {
        "question": "What countries share land borders with Suriname?",
        "answer": "French Guiana, Guyana, and Brazil"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country borders Suriname to the south?",
        "answer": "Brazil"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country borders Suriname to the west?",
        "answer": "Guyana"
    },
    {
        "question": "Autodromo Nazionale Monza is located in which country?",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which US state would you find Twenty Lake?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital city of England",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city would one find the Louvre in?",
        "answer": "Paris"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Peru?",
        "answer": "Lima"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where would one find Catalonia on a map?",
        "answer": "In Spain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Catalonia?",
        "answer": "Barcelona"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what national capital does the White Nile join the Blue Nile?",
        "answer": "Khartoum"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mount Suribachi is the highest point where?",
        "answer": "Iwo Jima"
    },
    {
        "question": "The word `serendipity` comes from Serendip, the Persian name for what island?",
        "answer": "Sri Lanka"
    },
    {
        "question": "What island was once called Van Diemen`s Land?",
        "answer": "Tasmania"
    },
    {
        "question": "What island is home to nearly all the lemurs?",
        "answer": "Madagascar"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the lowest point in the United States?",
        "answer": "Death Valley, California"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the US state New Jersey?",
        "answer": "Trenton"
    },
    {
        "question": "What English city was known to the Romans as Venta Bulgarum?",
        "answer": "Winchester"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the US state North Carolina?",
        "answer": "Raleigh"
    }
]